控件在参数缺省时显示的数据都是在xml文件中给出的
Apparently the app shows dummy data that was hard coded into the XML file.
让我们使用ForecastAdapter
Let's make the actual weather data appear on screen
来展示真实的天气吧
using the forecast adapter.
现阶段  我们会为所有的子项都使用同一种布局
For now we'll use the same layout for all list items, but
在之后的视频中  我们会将当天的天气改成另一种布局显示
we'll incorporate the today XML layout in the next video.
ForcastAdapter主要负责业务逻辑
Conceptually the forecast adapter manages the logics so that for
它会为游标里的每一行数据都创建对应的子项
each row of cursor we create corresponding list item.
回想一下在Lesson 1中讲到的ArrayAdapter
Think back on the explanation in lesson one about the array adapter,
当时我们将数组作为ArrayAdapter的数据源
except instead of the datasource being an array,
而现在  数据源是来自于数据库中的游标
now the datasource is a cursor from the database.
子项的布局在list_item_forecast.xml中定义
The layout for the list item is defined in the list item forecast XML file.
得到一行游标  我们就会遍历这行游标
For one row of the cursor, we're going to go through and
并把数据获取出来
extract out the values.
由于游标中每一列数据都有对应的控件
We call it binding the data to the views because we take the value in
我们就通过遍历的方式将数据绑定到控件上
each column and we set it on to a different view.
比如
For example,
最高温度应该在最高温度的TextView上显示
the high temperature value would be set on to the high temperature text view.
最低温度也应该在最低温度的TextView上显示
The low temperature value will be set onto the low temperature text view.
再往下一行  以同样的方式绑定这些数据
For the next row, we bind the data in the same way
直到将游标里的数据和子项都进行了绑定
until we create a list item for each row in the cursor.
在我们的代码中定义了ForecastAdapter类
Currently, our code defines forecast adapter
它继承自CursorAdapter类
as extending from the cursor adapter class.
查看CursorAdapter文档
If you look at the documentation for
可知CursorAdapter是一个抽象类
cursor adapter, you'll notice that it's an abstract class.
有两个抽象方法需要重写  分别是bindView和newView
There are two abstract methods that we need to override, bindView, and newView.
newView方法返回一个新生成的子项布局  但是不包含数据
The newView method returns a new list item layout, but has no data in it.
在bindView方法中  传进一个子项布局
The bindView method takes an existing list item layout and
使用游标中的数据更新该布局的内容
updates it, with the data from the cursor.
在ForcastAdapter.java的newView方法中
In the forecast adapter class in the newView method
我们返回了list_item_forecast.xml的布局
we inflate the list item forecast XML layout.
然后在bindView方法里
Then in the bindView method,
将cursor中的数据和对应的控件进行绑定
we bind the data from the cursor to the individual views.
试举一例  从cursor中查找到天气详情
For example, from the cursor we read out the weather description.
再找到id为list_item_forecast_textview的
Then we have to go through the view hierarchy to find the TextView
TextView控件
that has the id list_item_forecast_textview.
调用setText方法后  该TextView就可以显示真实的天气详情了
Once we find the TextView, then we can update it with the right description.
我们提供了bindView方法代码的一个Gist链接
We've provided a gist of code for
来帮你快速入门
the bindView method, to help you get started.
不过我们还是留下了一些空白需要你自己补充完整
But we left some to-dos in there for you to do.
我们还在Gist上提供了一些工具类方法
In the gist, we also included some helper methods and strings for
和字符串键值对
date formatting.
这是因为
That's because,
现阶段  所有的数据都是以同一种格式显示出来的
in our current implementation, all the dates are displayed in the same way.
在之前设计好的框架中  我们考虑到日期格式需要更符合用户习惯
In the wire frames, though, we have a more friendly date format.
比如将日期显示成今天  明天  星期三  星期四之类的
Such as today, tomorrow, Wednesday, Thursday, etc.
我们提供的工具类方法
Here's the logic for
就是将日期转换成这种用户友好型的格式
what the helper method does to get the friendly date string.
比如本周内的日期  会把它说成今天  或者明天  或者星期几
If it's this week, it says today or tomorrow or the day of the week.
如果不是本周  就会使用Mon June 8这种格式
If it's more than a week out, then we use the format Monday June 8 and so on.
编译并运行你的代码
After you compile and
带有真实数据的天气预报应用就做出来了
run the app, the actual weather forecast data should now be showing in the app.
而且日期更加人性化
And it's using a more friendly date format.
最后  别忘了检查一下这几个选项你是否都学会了
Check these boxes when you're done.